Renyuan Zhang (Leo)

Research Assistant Phone: (520) 878-8630

Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering Email: ryzhang@email.arizona.edu

University of Arizona Address: 2724 N Neruda Ln, Tucson, AZ 85712

Tucson, AZ 85721 GitHub: zrmaker

Summary of Qualifications

4+ years of research and engineering experience in the field of radar, automated driving, imaging and sensor networks.

Intensive experience in programming in MATLAB, C/C++, Python, Java and engineering related languages in Windows and Linux environment.

A strong self motivating ability and dedication to promoting effective teamwork. A strong ability to lead a research team.

Education

Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Aug. 2015 - Present

University of Arizona

Research interest: radar signal processing, radar imaging, automotive radar, micro-doppler signatures.

M.S. in Optical Sciences

Aug. 2013 - Aug. 2015

University of Arizona

Research interest: optical imaging, line CCD, optical coherence tomography.

B.S. in Optoelectronic Engineering

Sept. 2009 - June 2013

Chongqing University

Publications

Journal Articles

R. Zhang and S. Cao, "3D Imaging Millimeter Wave Circular Synthetic Aperture Radar," *Sensors*, vol. 17, no. 6, p. 1419, June 2017.

Proceedings

- **R. Zhang** and S. Cao, "Support Vector Machines for Classification of Automotive Radar Interference," 2018 IEEE Radar Conference (RadarConf), Oklahoma City, OK, USA, April 2018. (in press)
- **R. Zhang** and S. Cao, "Compressed Sensing For Portable Millimeter Wave 3D Imaging Radar," 2017 IEEE Radar Conference (RadarConf), Seattle, WA, USA, May 2017, pp. 0663-0668.
- **R. Zhang** and S. Cao, "Portable Millimeter Wave 3D Imaging Radar," 2017 IEEE Radar Conference (RadarConf), Seattle, WA, USA, May 2017, pp. 0298-0303.

Dissertation and Thesis

- **R. Zhang** and K. Kieu, "Fiber Based Spectral Domain Optical Coherence Tomography: Mechanism and Clinical Applications," *University of Arizona*, 2015.
- **R. Zhang** and C. Li, "Surface-Enhanced Raman Scattering Substrate Synthesis and Characterization", *Chongqing University*, 2013.

Professional Experience

- Research Assistant at Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering Advisor: Dr. Siyang Cao, *University of Arizona*.

2015 - Present

- Radar Interference Detection, Classification and Mitigation

Fields: Radar Interference (RFI), Machine Learning, DSP.

Working on simulation of 77 GHz automotive radar interference. Use machine learning methods to classify different interference range-doppler response results from PRI difference, long chirp, etc.. And use filter design, circular scanning array antenna and advanced signal processing methods to mitigate interference.

- Automotive Radar Measurement with 3D Printing Lens

With Min Liang and Jin-pil Tak.

Fields: Automotive Radar, DSP, RF and Antenna Theory, Antenna Measurements.

Measurements of real automobile with 77 GHz automotive radar and 3D priting lens (URL: http://techlaunch.arizona.edu/news/startup-licenses-ua-invented-radar-system).

 3D Imaging Millimeter Wave Circular Synthetic Aperture Radar Fields: SAR, DSP, Radar Imaging, mmWave Imaging, Compressed Sensing. Paper published above.

 Sensor Engineer at TuSimple TuSimple LLC, Tucson, AZ. Sept. 2017 - Mar. 2018

- Autoliv® 77 GHz multi-mode radar ROS driver development and evaluation.
- Bosch® 77 GHz long-range radar and mid-range radar ROS driver development.
- Delphi® 77 GHz electronic scanning radar evaluation.
- Hokuyo® URG-04LX-UG01 Scanning Laser Rangefinder development and truck trailer monitor/filter project.
- Industrial radar signal filtering and target recognition development.

 Research Assistant of Nonlinear Optics at College of Optical Sciences Advisor: Dr. Khanh Kieu, *University of Arizona*. 2014 - 2015

 Thesis on Fiber Based Spectral Domain Optical Coherence Tomography: Mechanism and Clinical Applications

Fields: Optical Imaging, Interference, Lens Design, Spectral Domain Analysis, Fiber Optics, Medical Imaging, OCT.

 Research Assistant of Applied Optics at College of Optical Sciences Advisor: Dr. Rongguang Liang, *University of Arizona*. 2013 - 2014

Confocal Microscopy

Fields: Optical Imaging, Spatial Pinhole, Lens Design.

Skills

Programming: Mathworks MATLAB, NI LabVIEW, Eclipse JAVA, Visual Studio C/C++/C#, Python, R,

CSS, HTML and Intel FPGA SDK.

RF & EM: ANSYS EM suite and Keysight ADS.

Sensors: Radar, LiDAR, CMOS, CCD, sonar, depth sensor, microphone and Microsoft Kinect. **Machine Learning:** SVM, ANN, RNN, *k*-NN, *k*-means, naive Bayes, decision tree and mixture model (Gaus-

sian).

CAD & Production: SOLIDWORKS, Autodesk AutoCAD and Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator,

Premiere Pro).

Operating Systems: Windows and Ubuntu.

Embedded Systems: NI control and acquisition suites and Arduino.

Others: Digital signal processing (DSP), imaging processing, range-doppler processing, con-

troller area network (CAN) for sensor fusion.

References

Dr. Siyang Cao
Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering *University of Arizona*Email: caos@email.arizona.edu
Phone: 520-621-4521